很久很久以前，在一个遥远的银河中…
《星球大战：帝国反击战》
对于反抗军来说，这是一个黑暗的时刻
虽然死星已经被摧毁
帝国部队把反抗军逼出了他们的秘密基地，并且在银河中苦苦追赶
为了躲避丧心病狂的帝国舰队
一队自由战士在天行者卢克的带领下
在遥远的霍斯星系的冰天雪地中建立了一个秘密基地
邪恶的达斯·维德勋爵为了找到年轻的天行者
派出了几千个探测机器人，其魔掌遍布整个银河
三号呼叫七号
EchoThree to Echo Seven.
汉，老伙计，能听到吗？
Han, old buddy, do you read me?
很清楚，小子，怎么了？
Loud and clear, kid. What's up?
我转完一圈了，没发现任何生命迹象
I finished my circle. I don't pick up any life readings.
这里冰天雪地的，没有那么多生命体的
There isn't enough life on this ice cube to fill a space cruiser.
传感器已经安装完毕，我正在返程
The sensors are placed. I'm going back.
好的，等会见
Ri ght. I'll see you shortly.
一颗流星在附近坠落
There's a meteorite that hit the ground near here.
我过去察看一下，不会太久
I want to check it out. It won't take long.
稳住
Steady.
稳住，怎么了？你闻到什么了吗？
Steady, girl. What's the matter? You smell something?
楚伊，楚伊？
Chewie. Chewie?
没事，别发脾气
All right. Don't lose your temper.
我马上就过来帮你
I'll come right back and give you a hand.
索罗
Solo.
没发现生命迹象，将军，传感器已经就位
No sign of life out there, General. The sensors are in place.
- 如果有什么东西，我们会发现的 - 天行者指挥官回来了吗？
- You'll know if anything comes around. - Commander Skywalker reported in yet?
没有，他去检查一颗在他附近坠落的流星了
No. He's checking out a meteorite that hit near him.
由于流星的原因，对入侵战舰的探测可能受到影响
With all the meteor activity, it's gonna be difficult to spot approaching ships.
将军，我要走了，我不能呆在这里了
General, I gotta leave. I can't stay any more.
- 真遗憾 - 有人悬赏捉拿我
- I'm sorry to hear that. - There's a price on my head.
如果我不还钱给赫特族的贾巴，我就死定了
If I don't pay offJabba the Hutt, I'm a dead man.
被人追杀可不好过
A death mark's not an easy thing to live with.
你是一名优秀的战士，索罗，我可不想失去你
You're a good fighter, Solo. I hate to lose you.
谢谢夸奖，将军
Thankyou, General.
恩，殿下，就这样了，是吗？
Well, Your Highness, guess this is it.
没错
That's right.
不要总是对我这么冷淡，再见，公主
Don't get all mushy on me. So long, Princess.
汉
Han.
- 怎么了，殿下 - 我以为你决定留下呢
- Yes, Your Highnessness. - I thought you had decided to stay.
我们在奥德曼特遇到的那个赏金猎人让我改变了主意
The bounty hunter we ran into in Ord Mantell changed my mind.
汉，我们需要你
Han, we need you.
- 我们需要？ - 是的
- We need? - Yes.
- 那么你呢？ - 我需要？
- What about you need? - I need?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
- 你可能不吧 - 你说我该知道些什么？
- You probably don't. - What precisely am I supposed to know?
承认吧，你让我留下来完全是因为你对我的感觉
Come on. You want me to stay because of the way you feel about me.
是的，你对我们有很大帮助，你天生就一个领导者
Yes. You're a great help to us. You're a natural leader.
不，我不是说这个
No. That's not it.
承认吧
Come on.
- 说出来吧 - 你不要自我感觉太好
- Come on. - You're imagining things.
我有吗？那你跟着我干什么？
Am I? Then why are you following me?
你是怕我走了，都不和你吻别
Afraid I'd leave without giving you a goodbye kiss?
- 我吻一个伍基族人都不亲你 - 要吻它我可以帮你安排
- I'd just as soon kiss a Wookiee. - I can arrange that.
你可以好好亲它一下
You could use a good kiss!
别责怪我，我可没叫你打开加热器
Don't blame me. I didn't askyou to turn on the thermal heater.
在公主的房间里我只是说我很快结冰了
I merely commented that it was freezing in the princess's chamber.
确实快结冰了
It's supposed to be freezing.
我们怎么才能把她的衣服弄干？我真的没法子
How we're going to dry her clothes I really don't know.
哦，快关掉
Oh, switch off!
你干什么把这个拆开？我们要离开这里
Why did you take this apart now? I'm trying to get us out of here.
- 打扰一下 - 快把它们装回去
- Excuse me. - Put them back together right now.
- 我能和你说句话吗？ - 什么事？
- Might I have a word? - What do you want?
莉娅公主一直都试图通过通讯器联系你
Princess Leia's been trying to get you on the communicator.
我把它关了，我不想和她说话
I turned it off. I don't want to talk to her.
莉娅公主在担心卢克主人，他到现在都没回来
Princess Leia is wondering about Master Luke. He hasn't come back.
- 她不知道他在那里 - 我也不知道他在哪
- She doesn't know where he is. - I don't know where he is.
- 没人知道 - 什么意思？没人知道？
- Nobody knows where he is. - What do you mean, nobody knows?
甲板官
Deck Officer.
- 甲板官 - 对不起长官，我可以…
- Deck Officer. - Excuse me, sir. Might I…
你知道天行者指挥官在哪里吗？
Do you know where Commander Skywalker is?
我没看到他，可能他从南门进来的
I haven't seen him. It's possible he came in the south entrance.
什么叫可能？为什么不去看一下？
It's possible? Why don't you go find out?
- 外面快天黑了 - 是，长官
- It's getting dark out there. - Yes, sir.
打扰一下，长官，我可以知道现在怎么了吗？
Excuse me, sir. Might I enquire what's going on?
- 为什么不？ - 奇怪的人
- Why not? - Impossible man.
过来，R2，我们去找莉娅公主
Come along, R2. Let's find Princess Leia.
只在我们之间说，我认为卢克主人现在一定处在危险中
Between ourselves, I think Master Luke is in considerable danger.
天行者指挥官没有从南门进入
Commander Skywalker hasn't come in the south entrance.
- 也许他忘了登记 - 不大可能 超音速战斗机准备好了吗？
- Maybe he forgot to check in. - Not likely. Are the speeders ready?
没有，我们没法让他们适应低温
Not yet. We're having trouble adapting them to the cold.
- 只好骑骆驼出去了 - 外面气温急剧下降
- We'll have to go out on tauntauns. - The temperature's dropping too rapidly.
没错，但是我的朋友就在外面
That's right, and my friend's out in it.
你的骆驼在你到达第一个标记处之前就会冻僵的
Your tauntaun will freeze before you reach the first marker.
那么，我们就在地狱再见吧
Then I'll see you in hell.
快进来吧，R2
You must come along now, R2.
我们真的做不了什么了
There's really nothing more we can do.
我的关节都快结冰了
And my joints are freezing up.
别这么说，我们当然会再见到卢克主人
Don't say things like that. Of course we'll see Master Luke again.
他一定会好好的，你看着吧
And he'll be quite all right. You'll see.
你这个短路的笨小孩，他一定会没事的
Stupid little short circuit. He'll be quite all right.
长官，所有的巡逻部队都回来了，仍然没有
Sir, all the patrols are in. Still no…
没有天行者或索罗的消息
Still no contact from Skywalker or Solo.
莉娅主人，R2说他收不到任何的信号
Mistress Leia, R2 says he's been quite unable to pick up any signals…
但是他承认他所能接受的范围太小，不应该放弃所有的希望
although he admits that his own range is far too weak to abandon all hope.
殿下，我们今晚可能不能多做什么了
Your Highness, there's nothing more we can do tonight.
护罩门必须要关闭
The shield doors must be closed.
- 关闭闸门 - 是，长官
- Close the doors. - Yes, sir.
R2说生存的概率是725分之一
R2 says the chances of survival are 725-to-1.
当然，大家都知道R2是会犯错误的…
Actually, R2 has been known to make mistakes…
常常
from time to time.
哦，天哪！哦，天哪！
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
别为卢克主人担心，我肯定他会没事的
Don't worry about Master Luke. I'm sure he'll be all right.
他很聪明，嗯，对于一个人类来说
He's quite clever, you know, for a human being.
卢克
Luke.
本？
Ben?
你需要去达古巴星系？
You will go to the Dagobah system.
达古巴星系？
Dagobah system?
在那里，你要向尤达学习…
There you will learn from Yoda…
那个指导我的绝地导师
the Jedi master who instructed me.
不要这样，卢克，告诉我你没死
Don't do this, Luke. Give me a sign here.
- 时间不多了 - 本
- Not much time. - Ben.
坚持一下，小子
Hang on, kid.
达古巴星系，达古巴
Dagobah system. Dagobah.
这可能不好闻，小子…
This may smell bad, kid…
尤达
Yoda.
但这会在我打开护罩之前让你保暖
but it'll keep you warm till I get the shelter up.
本，达古巴
Ben. Dagobah.
真是太难闻了
I thought they smelled bad…
在外面
on the outside.
呼叫总部，有发现
Echo Base, I've got something.
不是很清楚，但是有可能是生命体
Not much, but it could be a life form.
天行者指挥官，收到吗？
Commander Skywalker, do you copy?
这里是罗格二号
This is Rogue Two.
索罗船长，收到吗？
Captain Solo, do you copy?
天行者指挥官，收到吗？
Commander Skywalker, do you copy?
这里是罗格二号
This is Rogue Two.
早晨好，谢谢你们来接我们
Good morning. Nice ofyou guys to drop by.
呼叫总部，这里是罗格二号
Echo Base, this is Rogue Two.
我找到他们了，重复，我找到他们了
I've found them. Repeat. I've found them.
卢克主人，长官，看到你恢复真是太好了
Master Luke, sir, it's so good to see you fully functional again.
- 谢谢你，3PO - R2也松了一口气
- Thanks, 3PO. - R2 expresses his relief also.
感觉如何，小子？看起来还不错嘛
How ya feelin', kid? You don't look so bad to me.
你看起来很好，足以扯下刚达的耳朵
You look strong enough to pull the ears off a gundark.
- 多亏了你 - 你可欠我两个人情了，小子
- Thanks to you. - That's two you owe me, junior.
嗯，阁下…
Well, Your Worship…
看起来你成功了，把我多留了一会
Iooks like you managed to keep me around for a little while longer.
我和这件事可没有关系
I had nothing to do with it.
莱肯将军觉得直到我们开启能量场以前
General Rieekan thinks it's dangerous for any ships to leave…
任何的飞船起飞都是危险的
until we've activated the energy field.
这个说法不错
That's a good story.
我认为，你是不想让像我这样英俊的男子走出你的视线
I thinkyou just can't bear to let a gorgeous guy like me out ofyour sight.
我真不知道你哪来的这些错觉
I don't know where you get your delusions, laser brain.
笑什么笑，你这个混球…
Laugh it up, fuzzball…
你没看到我们单独在南方通道的时候
but you didn't see us alone in the south passage.
他向我表达了真情
She expressed her true feelings for me.
我的…
My…
你怎么这样，你这个愚蠢的…
Why, you stuck-up, half-witted…
肮脏的混蛋！
scruffy-looking nerf herder!
说谁肮脏？
Who's scruffy-lookin'?
一定是我说中了什么她才会怒成这样，对吧，小子？
I must have hit close to the mark to get her riled up like that, huh, kid?
你一点都不了解女人
I guess you don't know everything about women yet.
指挥部人员，请到指挥中心来
Headquarters personnel, report to command centre.
别想那么多
T ake it easy.
我们走了
Excuse us, please.
公主，我们有客人了
Princess, we have a visitor.
在12区发现有东西在东前进
We picked up something outside Zone 12 moving east.
- 是金属 - 不是这里的生物
- It's metal. - It couldn't be one of those creatures.
- 可能是我们的战斗机呀 - 不，等等
- Could be one of our speeders. - No. Wait.
收到一些很微弱的东西
There's something very weak coming through.
长官，我熟悉六百万种交流的方式
Sir, I am fluent in six million forms of communication.
这种信号不是联盟使用的，有可能是帝国的编码
This signal is not used by the Alliance. It could be an imperial code.
看来不太友好，楚伊，我们去看看
It isn't friendly. Chewie, let's check it out.
把罗格10号和11号传送到38号舱
Send Rogues 10 and 11 to Station 38.
- 可能没剩下什么 - 那是什么东西？
- I'm afraid there's not much left. - What was it?
某种机器人，我的火力不是很猛
Droid ofsome kind. I didn't hit it that hard.
- 它肯定有自爆装置 - 是帝国的探测机器人
- Must have had a self-destruct. - An imperial probe droid.
很可能帝国已经发现我们在这里了
It's a good bet the Empire knows we're here.
最好开始撤离
We'd better start the evacuation.
- 司令官 - 什么事，上校？
- Admiral. - Yes, Captain?
我想我们发现了些什么，长官，报告只有一部分…
I think we've got something, sir. The report is only a fragment…
是发自一个在霍斯星系的探测机器人，就这么多线索了
from a probe droid in the Hoth system, but it's the best lead we've had.
在银河中我们有几千个这样的探测机器人
We have thousands of probe droids searching the galaxy.
- 我需要的是证据，不是线索 - 图像显示有生命迹象
- I want proof, not leads. - The visuals indicate life readings.
这不能说明什么，如果我们每个线索都深究的话…
It could mean anything. Ifwe followed up every lead…
但是，长官，霍斯星系是不应该存在人类的
But, sir, the Hoth system is supposed to be devoid of humans forms.
- 你发现了什么吗？ - 是的，大人
- You found something? - Yes, my lord.
就是它了，叛军就在那里
That's it. The rebels are there.
大人，有很多未标记的居住点
My lord, there are so many uncharted settlements.
- 有可能是走私犯… - 那就是系统所在
- It could be smugglers… - That is the system.
我肯定先行者就在那里
And I'm sure Skywalker is with them.
改变航向，飞往霍斯星系
Set your course for the Hoth system.
维耶斯将军，准备好人手
General Veers, prepare your men.
司令官
Admiral.
十组和七组将留下驾驶超音速战斗机
Groups Seven and 10 will stay behind to fly the speeders.
一旦所有的运输机装载完毕…
As soon as each transport is loaded…
撤离控制系统就会准许发射
evacuation control will give clearance for launch.
明白，长官
Right, sir.
好了，搞好了
All right. That's it.
试一下
Try it.
关掉！关掉！
Turn it off! Turn it off!
长官，要撤离T-47恐怕需要很长时间
Sir, it will take quite a while to evacuate the T-47s.
那些重型装置不管了，抓紧时间把小的模块装入运输机
Forget the heavy equipment. There's time to get small modules on the transports.
- 保重，长官 - 谢谢
- Take care, sir. - Thanks.
楚伊，要保重呀，知道吗？
Chewie, take care ofyourself, okay?
好了，好了
Okay, okay.
嗨，小子
Hi, kid.
肯定有什么原因，到另一头检查一下
There's gotta be a reason for it. Check it at the other end.
等一下
Wait a second.
- 你还好吗？ - 没事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
小心一点
Be careful.
你也是
You too.
将军，有一队灭星者
General, there's a fleet of Stardestroyers…
从四区的超空间飞来
coming out of hyperspace in Sector Four.
把所有的能量转到防护罩上来
Reroute all power to the energy shield.
拖住他们，直到所有的运输机起飞
We gotta hold them till all transports are away.
准备地面攻击
Prepare for ground assault.
- 那是什么，将军？ - 舰队已经驶出光速
- What is it, General? - The fleet has moved out of light speed.
扫描到一个能量场…
ComScan has detected an energy field…
正在保护霍斯星系中的六号行星
protecting an area of the sixth planet of the Hoth system.
那个能量场很强足以抵挡任何的轰炸
The field is strong enough to deflect any bombardment.
叛军发现我们了
The rebels are alerted to our presence.
奥泽尔司令官已经驶出光速，但是他太接近接近星系了
Admiral Ozzel came out of light speed too close to the system.
他可能想突袭
He felt surprise was wiser.
这家伙又笨又蠢
He is as clumsy as he is stupid.
将军，调集你的人马，准备地面攻击
General, prepare your troops for a surface attack.
是，大人
Yes, my lord.
维达勋爵
Lord Vader.
舰队已经驶出光速，我们正准备…
The fleet has moved out oflight speed, and we're preparing to…
这是你最后一次失败了，司令官
You have failed me for the last time, Admiral.
- 皮耶特上校 - 是，大人？
- Captain Piett. - Yes, my lord?
让部队在远离能量场的地方降落…
Make ready to land our troops beyond their energy field…
部署舰队，不要让任何东西逃掉
and deploy the fleet so that nothing gets off the system.
现在你来指挥，皮耶特司令官
You are in command now, Admiral Piett.
谢谢，维达勋爵
Thankyou, Lord Vader.
所有的驾驶员到北门集合
All troop carriers will assemble at the north entrance.
一旦装载完毕，重型运输机就起飞
The heavy transport ships will leave as soon as they're loaded.
每艘战舰由两架战斗机护送
Only two fighter escorts per ship.
能量场只能打开很短的时间…
The energy shield can only be opened for a short time…
你们必须紧随你们的运输机
so you'll have to stay very close to your transports.
两架战斗机对付一艘灭星者？
Two fighters against a Stardestroyer?
离子加农炮将发射几炮…
The ion cannon will fire several shots…
来保证没有任何的敌机挡住你们的去路
to make sure that any enemy ships will be out ofyour flight path.
等到能量场失效…
When you've gotten past the energy shield…
立即前往集结地点
proceed directly to the rendezvous point.
明白吗？
Understood?
好运
Good luck.
各自去自己的架舱吧，我们出发
Everybody to your stations. Let's go.
他们的主要目标肯定是发电机
Their primary target will be the power generators.
准备打开防护场
Prepare to open shield.
长管，叛军的舰船在朝我们的区域飞来
Sir, rebel ships are coming into our sector.
好，今天的第一笔收获
Good. Our first catch of the day.
离子炮准备
Stand by, ion control.
开火
Fire.
第一艘运输船已经突围
The first transport is away.
感觉好吗，长官？
Feeling all right, sir?
好极了，达克，你怎么样？
Just like new, Dak. How about you?
现在我觉得我一个人就可以把整个帝国掀翻
Right now I feel I could take on the whole Empire myself.
我明白你的意思
I know what you mean.
报告基地，3-T8，我们发现帝国的地面部队
Echo Station 3-T8. We've spotted imperial walkers.
帝国的地面部队在北部的山脊
Imperial walkers on the north ridge.
57号报告总部，我们正在前进
Echo Station 57, we're on our way.
好了，兄弟们，要小心了
All right, boys, keep tight now.
卢克，我没有无线电导引，我还没好
Luke, I have no approach vector. I'm not set.
稳住，达克
Steady, Dak.
启动D号攻击模式，现在！
Attack pattern Delta. Go now.
我来了
I'm coming in.
霍比，你在我旁边吗？
Hobbie, you still with me?
打不破他们的护甲
That armour's too strong for blasters.
罗格小组，用你们的叉子，发射线缆
Rogue Group, use your harpoons and tow cables.
去缠它们的腿，这是我们唯一的机会
Go for the legs. It might be our only chance.
准备好，达克
Stand by, Dak.
卢克，我们的发射控制器出了问题
Luke, we've got a malfunction in fire control.
我要切换到辅助设备
I'll have to cut in the auxiliary.
坚持一下
Just hang on.
坚持，达克，准备好投射线缆
Hang on, Dak. Get ready to fire that tow cable.
达克？
Dak?
是的，维达勋爵，我已经到达主发电机
Yes, Lord Vader. I've reached the main power generators.
护罩很快就会关闭，你可以准备登陆了
The shield will be down in moments. You may start your landing.
罗格三号
Rogue Three.
收到，罗格队长
Copy, Rogue Leader.
威治，我的炮手牺牲了，你要帮我来射击
Wedge, I've lost my gunner. You'll have to make this shot.
我来掩护你
I'll cover foryou.
准备好你的叉子，等我的下一次穿越
Set your harpoon. Follow me on the next pass.
来吧，罗格队长
Coming around, Rogue Leader.
稳住，罗格二号
Steady, Rogue Two.
发射叉子
Activate harpoon.
射得好，简森
Good shot, Janson.
再绕一圈
One more pass.
线缆放出，让它去
Cable out. Let her go!
脱离线缆
Detach cable.
线缆脱离了
Cable detached.
快呀！
Come on!
- 成功了 - 我看到了，威治，干得好！
- That got him! - I see it, Wedge. Good work.
我不认为我们可以在同一时刻保护两艘运输机
I don't think we can protect two transports at a time.
确实很冒险，但是我们坚持不了太久了
It's risky, but we can't hold out much longer.
我们没有选择了
We have no choice.
- 发射巡逻机 - 让剩下的地面人员撤离
- Launch patrol. - Evacuate remaining ground staff.
这根连那里，那根连那里，明白吗？
This one goes there, that one goes there. Right?
R2，现在你来照顾卢克主人了，明白吗？
R2, you take good care of Master Luke now, understand?
你也要照顾好自己
And do take good care ofyourself.
哦，天呐！哦，天那！
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
所有的部队都将登陆进行地面攻击
All troops will debark for ground assault.
准备瞄准主发电站
Prepare to target the main generator.
- 罗格二号，你还好吗？ - 嗯，我在你旁边，罗格队长
- Rogue Two, are you all right? - Yeah. I'm with you, Rogue Leader.
准备好叉子，我为你掩护
Set harpoon. I'll cover foryou.
- 来了 - 注意那里的交叉火力，伙计们
- Coming around. - Watch that crossfire, boys.
准备好三号位置
Set for position three.
稳住
Steady.
降低高度，现在发射
Stay tight and low. This is it!
霍比！
Hobbie!
我被击中了
I've been hit!
- 你还好吗？ - 你为什么还在这里？
- You all right? - Why are you still here?
- 我听到指挥中心被击中了 - 你应该离开了
- Heard the command centre had been hit. - You've got your clearance to leave.
别担心，我会离开的，但是首先，我必须让你登上飞船
Don't worry. I'll leave. First I'm gonna get you to your ship.
殿下，我们必须上这最后一艘运输机，这是我们唯一的希望
Your Highness, we must take this last transport. It's our only hope.
让所有12区的部队去南坡保护战斗机
Send all troops in Sector 12 to the south slope to protect the fighters.
帝国部队已经进入基地
Imperial troops have entered the base.
帝国部队已经进入基地…
Imperial troops have entered…
快！就这样吧！
Come on. That's it.
发出撤离信号
Give the evacuation code si gnal.
你也快上运输机
And get to your transports.
等等我
Wait for me.
开始撤退！
Begin retreat!
撤退！
Fall back!
- 到发电机的距离是多少？ - 17.28
- Distance to power generators? - 17.28.
瞄准，最大火力
Target. Maximum firepower.
运输机，我是索罗，起飞吧，我过不去了
Transport, this is Solo. Take off. I can't get to you.
我带她去乘鹰号，快起来
I'll get her out on the Falcon. Come on.
你们去哪里？快回来
Where are you going? Come back!
等等！等等我！停下！
Wait! Wait for me! Stop!
- 真是狗改不了吃屎 - 快来
- How typical. - Come on.
快来，金棒子，不然你就要被埋在这里了
Hurry up, goldenrod! You're gonna be a permanent resident.
等等我！
Wait! Wait!
- 这怎么样？ - 要不要我出去推一下？
- How's this? - Would it help if I got out and pushed?
- 索罗船长，索罗船长 - 可以考虑
- Captain Solo. Captain Solo. - It might.
长官，我想说…
Sir, might I suggest that you…
我还是等一下吧
It can wait.
这部老爷车根本不可能冲破封锁的！
This bucket ofbolts will never get past that blockade.
这个宝贝还有几个惊喜要给你
This baby's got a few surprises left in her.
快来！快来！
Come on! Come on!
启动，希望不要熄火
Switch over. Let's hope we don't have a burnout.
看到了吗？
See?
总有一点你会犯错误的，希望我当时能在场目睹
Someday you'll be wrong. I hope I'm there to see it.
按！
Punch it!
Ｒ２
R2.
准备好起飞
Get her ready for take-off.
祝你好运，卢克，集结点再见
Good luck, Luke. See you at the rendezvous.
别担心，R2，我们这就上路
Don't worry, R2. We're going. We're going.
没出什么问题，R2，我只是在设定新的路线
There's nothing wrong, R2. I'm just setting a new course.
我们不去和其他人集结，我们现在去达古巴星系
We're not gonna regroup with the others. We're going to the Dagobah system.
是的，R2
Yes, R2.
没事的，我再手动操纵一会
That's all right. I'd like to keep it on manual control for a while.
- 我看到他们了！我看到他们了！ - 你看到什么了？
- I saw 'em! I saw 'em! - Saw what?
灭星者，有两架紧跟着我们
Stardestroyers, two of'em coming right at us.
- 长官，我想说… - 让他闭嘴！
- Sir, might I suggest… - Shut him up or shut him down!
检查变流护盾
Check the deflector shield.
太好了，他们还能操纵
Great. Well, we can still outmanoeuvre them.
启动躲避功能
Take evasive action!
- 准备进入光速 - 长官，这不行…
- Prepare to jump to light speed. - But, sir!
他们靠近了
They're getting closer.
哦，这样吗？看这个
Oh, yeah? Watch this.
看什么？
Watch what?
- 我想有麻烦了 - 请让我说完，长官
- I think we're in trouble. - If I may say so…
我刚才发现超光速推进器被损毁了
I noticed earlier the hyperdrive motivator has been damaged.
- 我们不可能进入光速了 - 我们有麻烦了
- It's impossible to go to light speed. - We're in trouble.
水平推进器！
Horizontal boosters!
截流闸门！
Alluvial dampers.
都不是！把氢气扳手给我
That's not it. Bring me the hydrospanner.
我真不知道怎么才能解决
I don't know how we're gonna get out of this one.
楚伊！
Chewie!
那不是激光波，我们被什么东西击中了
That wasn't a laser blast. Something hit us.
汉，快上来
Han, get up here.
快走，楚伊！
Come on, Chewie!
小行星
Asteroids.
- 楚伊，设置到271 - 你要干什么
- Chewie, set 271. - What are you doing?
你不是要进入小行星带吧
You're not actually going into an asteroid field?
他们疯了才会跟着我们，不是吗？
They'd be crazy to follow us, wouldn't they?
你不用这样来引起我的注意
You don't have to do this to impress me.
长官，在小行星群中成功行驶的概率
Sir, the possibility of successfully navigating an asteroid field…
- 大约是3720分之一 - 别和我谈什么可行性
- is approximately 3, 720-to-1. - Never tell me the odds.
你不是说想看我犯错误吗？现在可能就是了
You said you wanted to be around when I made a mistake. This could be it.
我收回那句话
I take it back.
如果再多呆一会，我们会粉身碎骨的
We're gonna get pulverized ifwe stay out here much longer.
- 不想和你讨论这个 - 粉身碎骨？
- Ain't gonna argue with that. - Pulverized?
我现在来靠近一个大家伙
I'm going closer to one of the big ones.
- 靠近？ - 靠近？
- Closer? - Closer?
这简直是自杀！现在无处可走了
This is suicide! There's nowhere to go.
那里，看起来不错
There. That looks pretty good.
哪看起来不错？
What looks pretty good?
嗯，这样就好
Yeah. That'll do nicely.
对不起，我们到底去哪里呀？
Excuse me, ma'am, but where are we going?
我希望你清楚自己在干什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
嗯，我也希望
Yeah. Me too.
嗯，到了，达古巴
Yep, that's it. Dagobah.
不，我可不想改变主意
No, I'm not gonna change my mind about this.
没有监测到城市或是科技产物
I'm not picking up any cities or technology.
但是有大规模的生命迹象
Massive life form readings though.
下面肯定有生物存在
There's something alive down there.
放心吧，这里不会有帝国机器人的
Yes. I'm sure it's perfectly safe for droids.
我知道！我知道！
I know! I know!
所有的探测器都失灵了，我什么都看不到
All the scopes are dead. I can't see a thing.
坚持一下，马上开始着陆
Just hang on. I'm gonna start the landing cycle.
不，R2，你不要动，我到周围看看
No, R2, you stay put. I'll have a look around.
R2？
R2?
你在哪里？
Where are you?
R2！
R2!
你可要小心一点
You be more careful.
R2，那边走！
R2, that way.
R2！
R2!
哦，不
Oh, no.
你还好吗？起来
Are you all right? Come on.
你能出来太走运了
You were lucky to get out of there.
有什么坏了吗？
Anything broken?
如果你说不该来这里…
Ifyou're saying coming here was a bad idea…
我现在开始同意你了
I'm beginning to agree with ya.
R2，你说我们在这里干什么？
R2, what are we doing here?
感觉就像
It's like…
就像做梦一样…
something out of a dream or…
不知道
I don't know.
或许我疯了
Maybe I'm just going crazy.
什么事，司令官？
Yes, Admiral?
我们的舰只发现了千年鹰号，大人
Our ships have sighted the Millennium Falcon, lord…
但是他进入了一个行星群，如果冒险进入…
but it has entered an asteroid field, and we cannot risk…
我可不管什么行星群，司令官
Asteroids do not concern me, Admiral.
- 我只要那艘船，不要理由 - 是，大人
- I want that ship, not excuses. - Yes, lord.
我马上关掉所有东西，除了应急供电系统
I'm gonna shut down everything but the emergency power systems.
长官，我想问一下，会把我关掉吗？
Sir, I'm almost afraid to ask, but does that include shutting me down too?
不，我们需要你和鹰号通讯…
No. I need you to talk to the Falcon…
查出到底超光速推动器怎么了
find out what's wrong with the hyperdrive.
长官，很有可能这个小行星不很稳定
Sir, it's quite possible this asteroid is not entirely stable.
不很稳定？
Not entirely stable?
我可要感谢你说这些
I'm glad you're here to tell us these things.
楚伊，把这个能干的家伙带到后面去，把它插到推进器上
Chewie, take the professor in the back and plug him into the hyperdrive.
有时，真不知道你们人类是怎么想的
Sometimes I just don't understand human behaviour.
毕竟，我只是想做好自己的工作
After all, I'm only trying to do my job.
放开
Let go.
- 请放开我 - 干吗这么兴奋？
- Let go, please. - Don't get excited.
船长，被你抱着我一点都兴奋不起来
Captain, being held by you isn't quite enough to get me excited.
对不起，甜心
Sorry, sweetheart.
我可没空管你
I haven't got time for anything else.
准备好开始充电了吗？好的
Ready for some power? Okay.
让我看看
Let's see now.
插到这里，好了
Put that in there. There you go.
现在我要去找尤达
Now all I gotta do is find this Yoda…
如果他确实在这里的话
if he even exists.
这里可不像绝地导师呆的地方
It's really a strange place to find a Jedi master.
这地方让我毛骨悚然
This place gives me the creeps.
然而…
Still…
似乎又觉得有点熟悉
there's something familiar about this place.
不知道了
I don't know.
- 我感觉… - 感觉什么？
- I feel like… - Feel like what?
感觉到有人监视我
Like we're being watched.
放下你的武器，我可不想伤害你
Away put your weapon. I mean you no harm.
我只是想问问你来这里干什么
I am wondering, why are you here?
- 我来找人 - 找人？
- I'm looking for someone. - Looking?
你这不就找到了吗
Found someone you have, I would say.
没错
Right.
我想我能帮你的，真的
Help you I can. Yes.
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
我要找一个伟大的战士
I'm looking for a great warrior.
伟大的战士
Great warrior.
战争可不成就伟大
Wars not make one great.
放下
Put that down.
嘿，那时我的午餐
Hey! That's my dinner.
你怎么能吃大块的这玩意？
How you get so big eating food of this kind?
听着，朋友，我本不想在这个水坑着陆的
Listen, friend, we didn't mean to land in that puddle.
如果能把飞船弄出来就好了，可是现在出不去了
Ifwe could get our ship out, we would. But we can't.
哦，原来是搞不定飞船
Aw, cannot get your ship out.
快出来
Get out of there.
嘿，你会把它弄断的
Hey, you could have broken this.
别这样
Don't do that.
你尽给我添乱
You're making a mess.
嘿，把那个给我
Hey, give me that.
给我吧，不然我不帮你
Mine, or I will help you not.
我才不需要你的帮助，我只要我的灯
I don't want your help. I want my lamp back.
我还要用它走出这个肮脏的泥巴洞呢
I'm gonna need it to get out of this slimy mud-hole.
泥巴洞？肮脏？这可是我的家
Mud-hole? Slimy? My home this is.
R2，给他吧
R2, let him have it.
- 我的！我的！ - R2
- Mine! Mine! Mine! - R2.
可以离远一点吗，小矮人？我们还有很多事要做呢
Will you move along, little fella? We got a lot ofwork to do.
我要留下来帮你找你的朋友
Stay and help you I will. Find your friend.
我不是在找一个朋友，我在找绝地导师
I'm not looking for a friend. I'm looking for a Jedi master.
绝地导师，尤达
Jedi master. Yoda.
- 你在找尤达 - 你认识他吗？
- You seek Yoda. - You know him?
我会带你去找他
Take you to him I will.
是的，是的，但是要先吃东西
Yes, yes, but now we must eat.
来吧，好吃的，来吧
Come. Good food. Come.
来吧，来吧
Come, come.
Ｒ２…
R2…
留下来看着营地
stay and watch after the camp.
在我需要他的时候R2跑到哪里去了？
Where is R2 when I need him?
长官，我不知道这艘船是从哪里学的语言
Sir, I don't know where your ship learned to communicate…
它用的方言实在是太奇怪了
but it has the most peculiar dialect.
我想它是想说负轴上的电源耦合器被极化了
I believe it says the power coupling on the negative axis has been polarized.
我想你要更换一下
I'm afraid you'll have to replace it.
我当然会换的
Well, of course I'll have to replace it.
这里，还有楚伊…
Here. And, Chewie…
我想我们要更换负轴电源耦合器
I think we better replace the negative power coupling.
嘿，阁下，我只是想帮忙
Hey, Your Worship, I'm only trying to help.
可以不要这么叫我吗？
Would you please stop calling me that?
当然，莉娅
Sure, Leia.
- 你有的时候把事情弄得很糟 - 是的，确实如此
- You make it so difficult sometimes. - I do. I really do.
但是，你也可以对我好一点
You could be a little nicer though.
承认吧，有时你觉得我是对的
Admit it. Sometimes you think I'm all right.
有时，可能吧…
Occasionally, maybe…
当你不表现的像个无赖
when you aren't acting like a scoundrel.
无赖？
Scoundrel?
听起来不错
I like the sound of that.
- 停下 - 停下什么？
- Stop that. - Stop what?
快停下，我的手很脏
Stop that. My hands are dirty.
我的手也很脏，你在怕什么？
My hands are dirty too. What are you afraid of?
- 我怕？ - 你在发抖
- Afraid? - You're trembling.
我可没有
I'm not trembling.
你喜欢我，因为我是个无赖
You like me because I'm a scoundrel.
你的生活中没有多少无赖
There aren't enough scoundrels in your life.
我其实喜欢有礼貌的人
I happen to like nice men.
- 我就是个有礼貌的人 - 不，你才不是呢
- I'm a nice man. - No, you're not.
长官，长官
Sir, sir!
我隔离了逆功率能流耦合器
I've isolated the reverse power flux coupling.
谢谢！
Thankyou.
- 非常感谢你！ - 不用客气，长官
- Thankyou very much. - You're perfectly welcome, sir.
维达勋爵，那是他最后一次出现在我们的监视器上
That, Lord Vader, was the last time they appeared in any ofour scopes.
考虑到我们现在所承受的损失，他们肯定已经被消灭了
Considering the damage we've sustained, they must have been destroyed.
不，上校，他们还活着
No, Captain, they're alive.
让所有的能动的舰船扫荡行星群，直到他们被发现为止
I want every ship available to sweep the asteroid field until they are found.
- 维达勋爵 - 司令官，什么事？
- Lord Vader. - Yes, Admiral. What is it?
皇帝要求和你通话
The emperor commands you to make contact with him.
把舰船驶离小行星带
Move the ship out of the asteroid field…
要保证通话质量
so that we can send a clear transmission.
是，大人
Yes, my lord.
有什么事吗，我的主人？
What is thy bidding, my master?
“原力”中有一股很大的波动
There is a great disturbance in the Force.
我感觉到了
I have felt it.
我们有新的敌人了
We have a new enemy…
那个毁灭死星的年轻的叛军
theyoung rebel who destroyed the Death Star.
我还认为这个孩子…
I have no doubt this boy…
是安纳金天行者的后代
is the offspring ofAnakin Skywalker.
这个可能吗？
How is that possible?
自己感觉一下吧，维达勋爵
Search your feelings, L ord Vader.
你会知道这是真的
You will know it to be true.
他可能会毁灭我们
He could destroy us.
他只是一个孩子
He's just a boy.
欧比·旺帮不了他什么
Obi-Wan can no longer help him.
他身上的“原力”很强大
The Force is strong with him.
天行者的儿子决不能成为一个绝地武士
The son ofSkywalker must not become a Jedi.
如果能想办法让他转变
If he could be turned…
他会成为一个强大的盟友的
he would become a powerful ally.
是的
Yes.
他是一大笔财富
He would be a great asset.
能搞定他吗？
Can it be done?
他要么加入我们，要么就去死，主人
He will join us or die, master.
我知道这很好吃
I'm sure it's delicious.
我只是不理解为什么我们不能现在去见尤达？
I just don't understand why we can't see Yoda now.
耐心点，对于绝地武士来说也是需要吃饭的时间的
Patience. For the Jedi, it is time to eat as well.
吃，吃
Eat. Eat.
好烫
Hot.
好吃的东西，好吃
Good food. Good.
尤达离这里远吗？多久才能到他那里？
How far away is Yoda? Will it take us long to get there?
不远，尤达一点都不远
Not far. Yoda not far.
耐心点，很快你就能见到他了
Patience. Soon you will be with him.
根出叶，我来烧
Root leaf. I cook.
你为什么想成为一个绝地武士？
Why wish you become Jedi?
我想，大部分因为我的父亲吧
Mostly 'cause of my father, I guess.
父亲，他曾是一个强大的绝地武士
Father. Powerful Jedi was he.
- 强大的绝地武士 - 嘿，别闹了
- Powerful Jedi. - Oh, come on.
你怎么可能认识我父亲？你连我是谁都不知道
How could you know my father? You don't even know who I am.
我不知道我们在这里干什么，我们在浪费时间
I don't even know what I'm doing here. We're wasting our time!
我不能教他
I cannot teach him.
这个孩子根本没有耐心
The boy has no patience.
他会学着有耐心的
He will learn patience.
他心中有太多的仇恨
Much anger in him…
就像他父亲一样
Iike his father.
你教导我的时候，我难道不是这样吗？
Was I any different when you taught me?
就是这样
No.
- 他还没有准备好 - 尤达
- He is not ready. - Yoda.
我准备好了
I am ready.
我能成为一位绝地武士，本，告诉他我能…
I can be a Jedi. Ben, tell him I'm…
你准备好了？你怎么知道你准备好了？
Ready, are you? What know you ready?
我训练绝地武士已经有800年了
For 800 years have I trained Jedi.
到底该训练谁我有自己的原则
My own counsel will I keep on who is to be trained.
一名绝地武士必须有最强的责任心
A Jedi must have the deepest commitment…
最严肃的思维
the most serious mind.
我观察这个人很久了
This one a long time have I watched.
在他的一生中，他总是看着…
All his life has he looked away…
未来，远方
to the future, to the horizon.
他从来都没有考虑过他所在的地方
Never his mind on where he was…
他该干什么
what he was doing.
冒险
Adventure.
刺激
Excitement.
一名绝地武士不该渴望这些东西
A Jedi craves not these things.
他做事不考虑后果
You are reckless.
我也曾是这样，如果您记得的话
So was I, ifyou remember.
他太大了
He is too old.
是的，大到难以开始训练
Yes, too old to begin the training.
但是我学过很多东西
But I've learned so much.
- 一旦开始，他能完成吗？ - 我不会失败的
- Will he finish what he begins? - I won't fail you.
我一点都不害怕
I'm not afraid.
你以后会的
You will be.
你会的
- 长官，恕我斗胆直言… - 我不想听你说什么
- Sir, if I may venture an opinion… - I'm not interested in your opinion.
外面有东西
There's something out there.
- 哪里？ - 在洞的外面
- Where? - Outside in the cave.
就在那，听！
There it is. Listen!
- 我出去看看 - 你疯了吗？
- I'm going out there. - Are you crazy?
我刚把这堆废铁装好，我可不想谁把它再搞坏
I just got this bucket together. I won't let it get torn apart.
好，那我和你一起去
Then I'm going with you.
我想，我应该留下来守护舰船
I think it might be better if I stay behind and guard the ship.
哦，不
Oh, no.
这个地面感觉好奇怪
This ground sure feels strange.
似乎不像是岩石
It doesn't feel like rock.
水蒸气也很多
There's an awful lot of moisture in here.
我不知道，我有种不好的感觉
I don't know. I have a bad feeling about this.
是的
Yeah.
小心
Watch out!
没事，没事
It's all right. It's all right.
嗯，和我想得一样，是麦那蝙蝠
Yeah, that's what I thought… mynock.
楚伊检查一下舰船的其他部分，这玩意会粘在上面…
Chewie, check the rest of the ship and make sure there are no more attached…
还会咀嚼电缆
chewing on the power cables.
麦那蝙蝠？
Mynocks?
进入吧，我们把剩下的清理掉
Go inside. We'll clean them off if there are any more.
滚开！滚开！脏东西！开枪！
Go away! Go away, beastly thing! Shoo!
等一下
Wait a minute.
- 楚伊，快离开这里 - 帝国军还在外面呢
- Chewie, let's get out of here! - The Empire is still out there!
我们没时间讨论这个了
No time to discuss this in committee!
我可不是在和你讨论！
I am not a committee!
在小行星带你不能加到光速
You can't make thejump to light speed in this asteroid field.
快坐下，甜心，我们要起飞了
Sit down, sweetheart. We're taking off.
- 看啊！ - 我看见了
- Look! - I see it.
- 我们死定了！ - 这洞要塌了
- We're doomed! - The cave is collapsing.
- 这不是洞 - 什么？
- This is no cave. - What?
好的，跑啊
Yes, run.
很好
Yes.
绝地武士的力量来自于“原力”
A Jedi's strength flows from the Force.
但你要小心黑暗的一面，愤怒，恐惧，好战…
But beware of the dark side. Anger, fear, aggression…
这些都是黑暗之“原力”
The dark side of the Force are they.
战斗中，它们会轻松的占据你的心灵，在你的身体内流淌
Easily they flow, quick to join you in a fight.
一旦你走上了黑暗之路
If once you start down the dark path…
你就将一辈子臣服于它
forever will it dominate your destiny.
它会慢慢侵蚀你，好像它曾经对欧比·旺的学生做过的那样
Consume you it will, as it did Obi-Wan's apprentice.
维德
Vader.
- 黑暗之“原力”很强大吗？ - 不，不是这样的
- Is the dark side stronger? - No, no.
但是黑暗之路更快，更容易，更诱人
Quicker, easier, more seductive.
那我怎么能分清什么是好的，什么是不好的呢？
How am I to know the good side from the bad?
你会知道的
You will know…
当你心平气和之时
when you are calm, at peace…
被动防御之际
passive.
一个真正的绝地武士只用“原力”来获取知识和保护自己
A Jedi uses the Force for knowledge and defence…
而不是用它来攻击
never for attack.
- 但是告诉我为什么我不能… - 别问，没有为什么
- But tell me why I can't… - No. There is no why.
我今天不会再教你什么了
Nothing more will I teach you today.
不要考虑那些问题
Clear your mind of questions.
那里好像有什么
There's something not right here.
我感觉到寒冷
I feel cold.
- 死亡 - 那个地方…
- Death. - That place…
充满了黑暗之“原力”
is strong with the dark side of the Force.
那是恶魔的领域
A domain of evil it is.
但是你一定要进去
In you must go.
那里面有什么？
What's in there?
只有你带进去的东西
Only what you take with you.
你的武器…
Your weapons…
你不需要他们了
you will not need them.
那群赏金猎人，我们不需要他们那些混蛋
Bounty hunters. We don't need their scum.
- 遵命，长官 - 反叛者逃不出我们的手心
- Yes, sir. - Those rebels won't escape us.
长官，从灭星者级战舰复仇者号传来一条高优先级命令
Sir, we have a priority signal from the Stardestroyer Avenger.
好
Right.
谁抓住千年鹰号，就能获得重奖
There will be a substantial reward for the one who finds the Millennium Falcon.
你们可以采用任何手段…
You are free to use any methods necessary…
我只要求他们是活的
but I want them alive.
不能被分解
No disintegrations.
- 如您所愿 - 维德勋爵
- As you wish. - Lord Vader.
大人，我们找到他们了
My lord, we have them.
谢天谢地，我们总算逃出小行星带了
Thank goodness we're coming out of the asteroid field.
让我们离开这里吧，准备好光速旅行了吗？
Let's get out of here. Ready for light speed?
一，二…
One, two…
三！
three!
这不公平
It's not fair.
转换电路不工作，这不是我的错
Transfer circuits aren't working. It's not my fault.
- 无法跳跃到光速？ - 这真不是我的错
- No light speed? - It's not my fault.
先生，我们刚刚失去了我们后部的主偏导护盾
Sir, we just lost the main rear deflector shield.
我们的后舱再挨一击，我们就完蛋了
One more direct hit on the back quarter and we're done for.
调头
Turn her around.
调过头来！我要把全部能量放到前部的护盾上去
Turn her around! I'm gonna put all power in the front shield.
- 你要攻击？ - 面对帝国灭星者级战舰…
- You're gonna attack? - The odds of surviving…
直接攻击的存活机会…
a direct assault on an imperial Stardestroyer…
闭嘴！
Shut up!
他们转入攻击位置了
They're moving to attack position.
护盾开启
Shields up.
跟踪他们，他们可能还会再来这么一下
Track them. They may come around for another pass.
尼达船长，我们的搜索屏失去那船的踪迹了
Captain Needa, the ship no longer appears on our scopes.
他们不可能凭空消失，那么小的船不可能有隐身装置
They can't have disappeared. No ship that small has a cloaking device.
但是的确没有他们的踪迹
There's no trace of them.
船长，维德勋爵要最新战况
Captain, Lord Vader demands an update.
准备一艘飞船
Get a shuttle ready.
我会亲自去向维德勋爵道歉，对于追丢他们我负全责
I shall assume full responsibility for losing them and apologize to Lord Vader.
- 但是同时，继续搜寻整个区域 - 遵命，尼达船长
- Meanwhile, continue to scan the area. - Yes, Captain Needa.
用“原力”
Use the Force.
好的
Yes.
现在，提起那块石头
Now, the stone.
感觉它
Feel it.
专心！
Concentrate!
哦，不，我们永远出不去了
Oh, no. We'll never get it out now.
你太肯定了吧
So certain are you.
你总是做不到
Always with you it cannot be done.
你难道没有听到我说的话吗？
Hearyou nothing that I say?
师父，用“原力”移动石头是一回事
Master, moving stones around is one thing.
而移动这是另一回事，完全不同
This is totally different.
不，没什么不同
No. No different.
唯一的不同就是你的意念
Only different in your mind.
你必须忘记你学过的一切
You must unlearn what you have learned.
- 好吧，我试试看 - 不能试
- All right. I'll give it a try. - Try not.
或者做到
Do…
或者做不到
or do not.
没有试的余地
There is no try.
我不行，它太大了
I can't. It's too big.
大小不是关键
Size matters not.
看着我，你是不是想凭我的体格来判断我的能力？
Look at me. Judge me by my size, do you?
但是你不该这样…
And well you should not…
因为我有“原力”作我的同伴
for my ally is the Force.
一个威力无穷的同伴
And a powerful ally it is.
生命孕育了它
Life creates it…
让它逐渐变强
makes it grow.
它的能量环绕着我们
Its energy surrounds us…
约束着我们
and binds us.
我们靠的是发光体，不是这些坚硬的肌肉
Luminous beings are we, not this crude matter.
你必须要感受你身边的“原力”
You must feel the Force around you.
这里，在你和我之间…
Here, between you, me…
还有树木，岩石…
the tree, the rock…
各处
everywhere.
没错…
Yes…
即使在这块土地和那艘船之间
even between the land and the ship.
你要求的是无法做到的
You want the impossible.
我无法相信
I don't believe it.
这就是你为什么会失败
That is why you fail.
我接受你的道歉，尼达船长
Apology accepted, Captain Needa.
维德勋爵，我们已经搜索了临近区域，但是一无所获
Lord Vader, our ships have completed their scan and found nothing.
如果千年鹰号进入了光速飞行
If the Millennium Falcon went into light speed…
它现在该出现在银河的另一边了
it'll be on the other side of the galaxy now.
让所有单位注意
Alert all commands.
根据已知的他们最后的航线，计算出他们所有可能的目的地
Calculate every possible destination along their last known trajectory.
- 遵命，大人，我们会找到他们的 - 不要再让我失望…
- Yes, my lord. We'll find them. - Don't fail me again…
司令官阁下
Admiral.
布署舰队，让所有单位注意
Alert all commands. Deploy the fleet.
索罗船长，这一次你玩过火了
Captain Solo, this time you have gone too far.
不，我不会保持沉默的，楚贝卡
I will not be quiet, Chewbacca.
楚贝卡，为什么就没人听我说呢？
Why doesn't anyone listen to me?
帝国舰队即将分散了
The fleet's beginning to break up.
准备手动放下登陆爪
Go stand by the manual release for the landing claw.
我实在不懂这能对我们有何帮助
I really don't see how that's going to help.
在这种极端环境下，投降绝对是可以接受的一个方案
Surrender is a perfectly acceptable alternative in extreme circumstances.
帝国也许会对我们足够仁慈…
The Empire may be gracious enough…
- 谢谢你 - 你下一步打算怎么做？
- Thankyou. - What did you have in mind next?
如果他们严格按照帝国舰队规程来做
If they follow standard imperial procedure…
他们会先把垃圾扔下，然后进入光速飞行
they'll dump their garbage before they go to light speed.
- 然后我们就可以慢慢漂走了 - 是啊，和一堆垃圾为伍
- Then we just float away. - With the rest of the garbage.
然后怎么办？
Then what?
然后我们得在这附件找一个安全的港口
Then we gotta find a safe port somewhere around here.
有什么建议吗？
Any ideas?
- 我们在哪里？ - 阿诺亚特星系
- Where are we? - The Anoat system.
阿诺亚特星系，这可没几个安全港
The Anoat system. There's not much there.
恩，等等，真有意思
Oh, wait. This is interesting.
- 兰多 - 兰多星系？
- Lando. - Lando system?
兰多不是个星系，是个人，兰多·卡尔瑞辛
Lando's not a system. He's a man. Lando Calrissian.
牌手，赌徒
Card player, gambler.
- 一个无赖，你会喜欢他的 - 谢谢
- A scoundrel. You'd like him. - Thanks.
贝斯平星，有点远，不过我想我们能抵达那里的
Bespin. It's pretty far, but I think we can make it.
- 一个采矿区？ - 没错，提巴那瓦斯矿
- A mining colony? - Yeah, a tibanna gas mine.
兰多从某人手中骗来的
Lando conned somebody out of it.
兰多和我可是很久前就在一起了
We go back a long way, Lando and me.
- 你能相信他吗？ - 不能
- Can you trust him? - No.
但是他对帝国也没什么好感，这个我能向你保证
But he's got no love for the Empire. I can tell you that.
要出发了，楚伊，准备好，分离
Here we go, Chewie. Stand by. Detach.
你终于等到这一刻了
You do have your moments.
垃圾不多，不过的确有一些
Not many of them, but you do have them.
集中精神
Concentrate.
感受“原力”的流动
Feel the Force flow.
好
Yes.
很好
Good.
冷静
Calm.
好
Yes.
透过“原力”，你会看到很多东西
Through the Force, things you will see.
过去、未来，世界各地
Other places. The future. The past.
逝去已久的老朋友
Old friends long gone.
控制，控制住
Control, control.
你必须学会控制
You must learn control.
我看到一座云中之城
I saw a city in the clouds.
那有你的朋友
Friends you have there.
- 他们正在受苦 - 你看见的是未来
- They were in pain. - It is the future you see.
未来？
Future?
他们会死吗？
Will they die?
很难讲
Difficult to see.
未来总是在不停变化的
Always in motion is the future.
我要去找他们
I've gotta go to them.
你必须做个决定，如何才能最好的帮助他们
Decide you must how to serve them best.
如果你现在离开，你可以去帮助他们
Ifyou leave now, help them you could…
但是他们为之奋斗、受苦的一切也将因此而毁灭
but you would destroy all for which they have fought and suffered.
不，我没有降落许可
No, I don't have a landing permit.
我在找兰多·卡尔瑞辛
I'm trying to reach Lando Calrissian.
等等！让我解释一下！
Wait a minute! Let me explain!
你不能偏离你现在的航线
You will not deviate from yourpresent course.
- 他们脾气真差，对吧？ - 我还以为你认识这个家伙
- Rather touchy, aren't they? - I thought you knew this person.
那是很久以前了，他肯定把那些事都忘了
That was a long time ago. I'm sure he's forgotten about that.
你被允许在327号平台上着陆
Permission granted to land on Platform 327…
谢谢你
Thank you.
没什么好担心的，兰多和我很久前就认识了
Nothing to worry about. We go way back, Lando and me.
谁在担心？
Who's worried?
没人迎接我们
No one to meet us.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like this.
- 你喜欢什么？ - 他们毕竟让我们着陆了
- What would you like? - They did let us land.
我说，别担心，一切都会好的
Look, don't worry. Everything's gonna be fine.
相信我
Trust me.
看见没有？我的朋友来了
See? My friend.
睁大你的眼睛
Keep your eyes open.
嘿
Hey.
嘿，你这个令人作呕，阴险狡诈，无恶不作的骗子
Why, you slimy, double-crossing, no-good swindler.
你干了这么多事，居然还有胆子来这里啊
You've got a lot of guts coming here, after what you pulled.
你好吗，海盗朋友？见到你真高兴！
How you doin', you old pirate? So good to see you!
- 我从没想到还会再见到你 - 呃，他看起来很友善
- I never thought I'd see you again. - Well, he seems very friendly.
是啊，真友善
Yes. Very friendly.
你来这干嘛？
What are you doing here?
修理一下，我想你应该能帮上我的忙
Repairs. I thought you could help me out.
- 你对我的船做了些什么？ - 你的船？
- What have you done to my ship? - Your ship?
嘿，记住啊，你可是正大光明的把她输给我了
Hey, remember, you lost her to me fair and square.
你还好吗？楚贝卡？
How you doin', Chewbacca?
还和这个失败者混在一起？
Still hanging around with this loser?
你好，这一位是谁啊？
Hello. What have we here?
欢迎，我叫兰多·卡尔瑞辛，我是这个机构的管理者
Welcome. I'm Lando Calrissian. I'm the administrator of this facility.
- 请问你是？ - 莉娅
- And who might you be? - Leia.
欢迎你，莉娅
Welcome, Leia.
好啦，好啦，你这个油腔滑调的家伙
All right, all right. You old smoothie.
先生，你好，我是C-3PO，是沟通人类与机器人关系的专家
Hello, sir. I am C-3PO, human-cyborg relations.
我愿意为您… 呃，真的吗？
My facilities are at your… Well, really!
- 千年鹰什么地方坏了？ - 超空间引擎
- What's wrong with the Falcon? - Hyperdrive.
- 我会让我的人修好她的 - 好极了
- I'll get my people to work on her. - Good.
那船可是救了我好几次命呢
That ship saved my life quite a few times.
她是银河中最快的垃圾了
She's the fastest hunk of junk in the galaxy.
瓦斯矿如何？还能替你挣钱吗？
How's the gas mine? Still paying off foryou?
不如我想的好，我们只是个小据点，没法自给自足
Not as well as I'd like. We're a small outpost and not very self-sufficient.
我这里有各种供应问题
I've had supply problems of every kind.
人手也不足
I've had labour difficulties.
- 有什么好笑的？ - 你啊，听听你刚才说的
- What's so funny? - You. Listen to you.
你现在像个生意人了，是个负责的领导了
You sound like a businessman, a responsible leader.
谁会这么想啊？
Who'd have thought that, huh?
见到你让我回想起一些事情来了
Seeing you sure brings back a few things.
是的
Yeah.
是啊，我现在负责多了
Yeah, I'm responsible these days.
这是你获取成功的必要代价啊
It's the price you pay for being successful.
看到个熟人真好
Nice to see a familiar face.
太粗鲁了吧！
How rude!
听起来好里面有个R2型机器人
That sounds like an R2 unit in there.
我猜…有人吗？
I wonder if… Hello?
真有意思
How interesting.
- 你是谁？ - 哦，天啊，我非常抱歉
- Who are you? - Oh, my. I'm terribly sorry.
我不是有意闯入的，请不要起身
I didn't mean to intrude. Please don't get up.
卢克，你必须完成训练
Luke, you must complete the training.
我没法不去想脑中的那些影像，我必须去帮他们
I can't keep the vision out of my head. I've gotta help them.
你不能去
You must not go.
- 但是我不去的话，汉和莉娅会死的 - 你怎么知道
- But Han and Leia will die if I don't. - You don't know that.
即使尤达也看不清他们的命运
Even Yoda cannot see their fate.
但是我可以帮助他们，我能感觉到“原力”
But I can help them. I feel the Force.
但是你无法控制它
But you cannot control it.
现在对你来说是一个非常危险的时刻…
This is a dangerous time foryou…
你很容易就会被黑暗之“原力”所吸引
when you will be tempted by the dark side of the Force.
是的，是的，欧比·旺的话你总该听吧
Yes, yes. To Obi-Wan you listen.
想想那个洞
The cave.
还记得你在洞中的失败吗？
Rememberyour failure at the cave.
但是那之后我学到了很多
But I've learned so much since then.
尤达师父，我保证会回来完成我已经开始的训练
Master Yoda, I promise to return and finish what I've begun.
我向你保证
You have my word.
皇帝要的正是你和你的能力
It is you and your abilities the emperor wants.
因此你的朋友才会受苦
That is why your friends are made to suffer.
因此我才必须去帮他们
That's why I have to go.
卢克，我不想让你也投入皇帝那边，好像当年我失去维德那样
Luke, I don't want to lose you to the emperor the way I lost Vader.
你不会的
You won't.
他们必须被阻止，而所有的希望全系于你一身
Stopped they must be. On this all depends.
只有一个充分训练过的绝地武士，以原力为他的同伴…
Only a fully trained Jedi knight, with the Force as his ally…
才能制服维德和他的皇帝
will conquer Vader and his emperor.
如果你现在结束你的训练
Ifyou end your training now…
如果你选择那条快而容易的捷径，如同维德当年一样…
ifyou choose the quick and easy path, as Vader did…
你就将成为恶魔的代言人
you will become an agent of evil.
忍耐
Patience.
那就让汉和莉娅白白牺牲吗？
And sacrifice Han and Leia?
如果你能实现他们为之而战的正义…
If you honour what they fight for…
那就可以了
yes.
如果你决定与维德作战，你只能自己去
Ifyou choose to face Vader, you will do it alone.
我无法干涉
I cannot interfere.
我明白
I understand.
R2，给转换器点火
R2, fire up the converters.
不要屈从于仇恨
Don't give in to hate.
那会将你引向黑暗之路
That leads to the dark side.
维德很强大
Strong is Vader.
注意你学过的一切，它能拯救你
Mind what you have learned. Save you it can.
我会的
I will.
而且我一定会回来，我保证
And I'll return. I promise.
我早就告诉你了，他很鲁莽
Told you, I did. Reckless is he.
现在
Now…
局势更糟糕了
matters are worse.
那孩子是我们最后的希望了
That boy is ourlast hope.
不，还有另一个
No, there is another.
这船的修理差不多完成了，再有两三处修理，我们就大功告成了
The ship's almost finished. Two or three more things and we're in great shape.
越快越好，这有点不对劲
The sooner the better. Something's wrong here.
没人看见过3PO，也没人听说过任何他的下落
No one has seen or knows anything about 3PO.
他失踪太久了，不可能只是迷路
He's been gone too long to have gotten lost.
放松点
Relax.
我会和兰多谈谈的，看看他知道些什么不
I'll talk to Lando and see what I can find out.
我不相信兰多
I don't trust Lando.
这个嘛，我也不相信他，但是他是我的朋友
Well, I don't trust him either, but he is my friend.
而且，我们很快就要离开了
Besides, we'll soon be gone.
你准备离开了吗？
Then you're as good as gone, aren't you?
怎么了？
What happened?
哪里？
Where?
在一个垃圾堆找到他的？
Found him in a junk pile?
真是一团乱，楚伊，你觉得你能修好他吗？
What a mess. Chewie, you thinkyou can repair him?
- 兰多能找到人修好他的 - 不用了，谢谢
- Lando's got people that can fix him. - No, thanks.
对不起，我打扰你们了吗？
I'm sorry. Am I interrupting anything?
没有
Not really.
你看起来真美
You look absolutely beautiful.
你绝对应该和我们在一起，在云中生活
You truly belong here with us among the clouds.
谢谢你
Thankyou.
想和我一起用些点心吗？
Would you join me for a little refreshment?
当然，欢迎在座的每个人都去
Everyone's invited, of course.
你这个机器人出问题了？
Having trouble with your droid?
不，没问题，怎么了？
No. No problem. Why?
你看，因为我们是个小机构
You see, since we're a small operation…
我们不在帝国的管辖权限以内
we don't fall into the jurisdiction of the Empire.
- 那你是矿业工会的成员了？ - 不是
- So you're part of the Mining Guild? - No, not actually.
我们这个机构太小了，不引人注意
Our operation is small enough not to be noticed.
这样对所有人都好
Which is advantageous for everybody…
因为我们的顾客都不喜欢引起注意
since our customers are anxious to avoid attracting attention to themselves.
你就不怕帝国会找到你，关掉你这里吗？
Aren't you afraid the Empire's gonna find out, shut you down?
这的确是个危险，而且已经困扰我们很久了
It's been a danger that looms like a shadow over everything we've built.
但是事情有了发展，现在我们安全了
But things have developed that'll ensure security.
我刚刚做了笔交易，让帝国可以永远不干涉我们
I've just made a deal that'll keep the Empire out of here forever.
如果你能加入我们，我们会非常荣幸
We would be honoured ifyou would join us.
我别无选择，就在你来到之前，他们就来了
I had no choice. They arrived right before you did.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我也很遗憾
I'm sorry too.
不，3PO和他们在一起
No, 3PO's with them.
再坚持一下，我们马上就到了
Just hang on. We're almost there.
真是对不起，我不是有意闯入的
I'm terribly sorry. I didn't mean to intrude.
不，请不要起身
No, please don't get up.
突击士兵？这怎么会有？我们危险了
Stormtroopers? Here? We're in danger.
我得赶快通知其他人，哦，不！我被击中了
I must tell the others. Oh, no! I've been shot!
维德勋爵
Lord Vader.
等我抓住了天行者
You may take Captain Solo to Jabba the Hutt…
你就可以把索罗船长交给赫特族的贾巴了
after I have Skywalker.
他要是死了对我可没有用
He's no good to me dead.
他不会遭受任何永久性伤害的
He will not be permanently damaged.
维德勋爵，那莉娅和那个伍基族的家伙怎么办？
Lord Vader, what about Leia and the Wookiee?
他们要永远留在这个城市
They must never again leave this city.
这可不在我们的协定之中
That wasn't part of our agreement,
把汉交给这个赏金猎人也不符合约定！
nor was giving Han to this bounty hunter!
也许你觉得你受到了不公平对待？
Perhaps you thinkyou're being treated unfairly?
没有
No.
很好，要是我在这里被迫留下一群守卫可就太不幸了
Good. It would be unfortunate if I had to leave a garrison here.
这交易越来越差了
This deal is getting worse all the time.
哦，好，真不错，我喜欢这样
Oh, yes, that's very good. I like that.
我现在看不见了，肯定什么东西不对劲
Something's not right because now I can't see.
这样好多了
That's much better.
等等，等一下
Wait. Wait.
哦，天啊！你干了什么？
Oh, my! What have you done?
我被装反了！
I'm backwards!
你这个浑身跳蚤的毛球！
You flea-bitten furball!
只有你这种畸形生长的扫把头才会这么蠢…
Only an overgrown mophead like you would be stupid enough…
我很难受
I feel terrible.
他们干嘛要这么做？
Why are they doing this?
他们都不问我什么问题
They never even asked me any questions.
- 从这滚出去，兰多 - 闭嘴，听我说
- Get out of here, Lando. - Shut up and listen.
维德同意把莉娅和楚伊交给我
Vader's agreed to turn Leia and Chewie over to me.
他们只能待在这里了，但是他们是安全的
They'll have to stay here, but they'll be safe.
- 那汉怎么办？ - 维德已经把他交给赏金猎人了
- And Han? - Vader's given him to the bounty hunter.
- 维德想让我们都死 - 他根本就不在乎你们
- Vader wants us all dead. - He doesn't want you at all.
他只是要抓一个叫什么天行者的家伙
He's after somebody called Skywalker.
- 维德勋爵给他设了个陷阱 - 而我们就是诱饵？
- Lord Vader set a trap for him. - And we're the bait.
- 他正要来这里呢 - 好极了
- He's on his way. - Perfect.
你可真把我们修理的不错啊，对吧？
You fixed us all real good, didn't you?
朋友
My friend.
停！
Stop!
我尽力而为了
I've done all I can.
很遗憾我没法做的更好了，但是我也有我自己的麻烦
Sorry I couldn't do better, but I got my own problems.
是啊
Yeah.
你可真是个英雄呢
You're a real hero.
你对人可真是有一套
You certainly have a way with people.
这套器材是很原始…
This facility is crude…
但是应该足够冷冻天行者…
but it should be adequate to freeze Skywalker…
直到他见到皇帝陛下
for his journey to the emperor.
维德勋爵，有飞船接近了，X翼型
Lord Vader, ship approaching, X-wing class.
很好，监测天行者，并允许他降落
Good. Monitor Skywalker and allow him to land.
维德勋爵，我们只用这套器材做过碳化冷冻，这可能会杀死他的
Lord Vader, we only use this facility for carbon freezing. It might kill him.
我可不希望陛下要的人有什么损伤
I do not want the emperor's prize damaged.
我们先用索罗船长做实验
We will test it on Captain Solo.
如果你装好了我的腿，我才不会处在这种可笑的境地呢
Ifyou'd attached my legs I wouldn't be in this ridiculous position.
记住，楚贝卡，你对我负有责任…
Now remember, Chewbacca, you have a responsibility for me…
所以别做什么傻事
so don't do anything foolish.
朋友，这怎么了？
What's going on, buddy?
你将被碳化冷冻
You're being put into carbon freeze.
要是他死了怎么办？他对我来说值不少呢
What if he doesn't survive? He's worth a lot to me.
如果他死了，帝国会补偿你的损失的，把他弄进去
The Empire will compensate you if he dies. Put him in.
楚贝卡，停！
Chewbacca, stop!
不要，楚伊，停手！
No, Chewie, stop!
你会把我们都弄死的，停啊，我还不想死呢
You're going to get us all killed! Yes, stop. I'm not ready to die.
嘿！嘿！听我说
Hey! Hey! Listen to me.
楚伊，这样帮不了我
Chewie, this won't help me.
嘿，省点力气吧，还会有其他地方需要你的
Hey, save your strength. There'll be another time.
公主殿下
The princess.
你要照顾她
You have to take care of her.
你听见我的话了吗？
Do you hear me?
- 我爱你 - 我知道
- I love you. - I know.
怎么回事？转过去，我看不见了
What's going on? Turn round. I can't see.
他们把他碳化冷冻了
They've encased him in carbonite.
如果他能撑过冷冻过程的话
He should be quite well-protected…
他应该被保护的很好的
if he survived the freezing process, that is.
好啦，卡尔瑞辛，他活着吗？
Well, Calrissian, did he survive?
是的，他活着
Yes, he's alive.
而且正处于完美的休眠状态
And in perfect hibernation.
他现在是你的了，赏金猎人
He's all yours, bounty hunter.
重新布置一下这个房间，准备迎接天行者
Reset the chamber for Skywalker.
大人，天行者刚刚着陆
Skywalker has just landed, lord.
很好，一定要让他找来这里
Good. See to it that he finds his way in here.
卡尔瑞辛…
Calrissian…
把公主和那个伍基族的人带到我的船上去
take the princess and the Wookiee to my ship.
你说过他们应该要置于我的监控之下的
You said they'd be left under my supervision.
我改变主意了
I am altering the deal.
祈祷我不会再改变主意吧
Pray I don't alter it any further.
卢克，别来！是个陷阱！
Luke, don't! It's a trap!
是陷阱！
It's a trap!
愿“原力”与你同在，年轻的天行者
The Force is with you, young Skywalker.
但是你还不是一名绝地武士
But you are not a Jedi yet.
干的好
Well done.
把他们关进警卫塔，保持安静
Hold them in the security tower. And keep it quiet.
快走
Move.
- 你以为你在干嘛？ - 我们正逃离这里
- What do you thinkyou're doing? - We're getting out of here.
我早就计算好了，只是出了点小错误
I knew all along. It had to be a mistake.
你以为当你对汉做了这种事情以后…
Do you think that after what you did to Han…
- 我别无选择 - 你在干嘛？相信他吧！
- I had no choice. - What are you doing? Trust him!
我们理解这一点对吧，楚伊？他别无选择
We understand, don't we, Chewie? He had no choice.
我只是想帮忙而已
I'm just trying to help.
我们不需要你的什么帮助
We don't need any ofyour help.
什么？
What?
- 听起来他好像是说汉 - 还有机会救汉的
- It sounds like Han. - There's still a chance to save Han…
在东方…平台
at the east… platform.
我对于所发生的一切深感抱歉
I'm terribly sorry about all this.
毕竟，他只是个伍基族人
After all, he's only a Wookiee.
把索罗船长放到货舱里
Put Captain Solo in the cargo hold.
R2，你去哪了？
R2, where have you been?
等等，转过来，你这个毛茸茸的…
Wait. Turn around, you woolly…
快点！我们正要从赏金猎人那里把汉救出来
Hurry! We're trying to save Han from the bounty hunter.
呃，至少你还是完整的
Well, at least you're still in one piece.
看看我变成什么样子了
Look what's happened to me.
哦，不！楚伊，他们就在你后面！
Oh, no! Chewie, they're behind you!
你学到了不少啊，年轻人
You have learned much, young one.
我让你吃惊的地方还多着呢
You'll find I'm full of surprises.
你的命运注定是和我在一起，年轻的天行者
Your destiny lies with me, Skywalker.
欧比·旺早就知道这将会成为现实的
Obi-Wan knew this to be true.
太容易了
All too easy.
也许你不如皇帝陛下想像的那么强大
Perhaps you're not as strong as the emperor thought.
真令人感动
Impressive.
太令人感动了
Most impressive.
欧比·旺把你教的不错啊，你已经控制了你的恐惧
Obi-Wan has taught you well. You have controlled your fear.
现在释放你的愤怒吧
Now, release your anger.
只有你的仇恨才能摧毁我
Only your hatred can destroy me.
安全密码已经被改变了
The security code has been changed.
R2，快告诉计算机重设整个安全系统
R2, you can tell the computer to override the security systems.
R2，快点
R2, hurry.
注意，我是兰多·卡尔瑞辛，注意
Attention. This is Lando Calrissian. Attention.
帝国已经控制了这个城市
The Empire has taken control ofthe city.
我建议在更多的帝国部队还没来的时候，每个人都迅速撤离
I advise everyone to leave before more imperial troops arrive.
这边
This way.
这个，别怪我，我是个翻译
Well, don't blame me. I'm an interpreter.
我是没法知道计算机终端的能量套接字的
I'm not supposed to know a power socket from a computer terminal.
我们对千年鹰号的超空间引擎没有兴趣，他已经被修好了！
We're not interested in the hyperdrive on the Falcon. It's fixed!
赶快开门就好，你这个笨蛋！
Just open the door, you stupid lump!
我从未怀疑过你，太棒了！
I never doubted you for a second. Wonderful!
很痛啊！弯腰！你这个不长心眼的…喔！
That hurts! Bend down, you thoughtless… Ow!
快走！
Go!
我本来以为那个长毛野兽就是我的葬身之地了
I thought that hairy beast would be the end of me.
我当然看的更清楚了
Of course I've looked better.
你已经失败了，抵抗是没有意义的
You are beaten. It is useless to resist.
不要让你像欧比·旺一样被摧毁
Don't let yourself be destroyed as Obi-Wan did.
这没有出路的
There is no escape.
别逼我杀掉你
Don't make me destroy you.
你还不知道你的重要性
You do not yet realize your importance.
你只是刚开始了解你的力量
You have only begun to discoveryour power.
加入我吧
Join me…
我会完成你的训练
and I will complete your training.
而我们合力…
With our combined strength…
就可以结束这些破坏性的冲突
we can end this destructive conflict…
给银河带来秩序
and bring order to the galaxy.
我不会加入你的！
I'll never join you!
要是你知道了黑暗之路的力量的话，你会的
Ifyou only knew the power of the dark side.
欧比·旺从来没有告诉过你你父亲怎么样了吧
Obi-Wan never told you what happened to your father.
他告诉我很多了
He told me enough.
他对我说是你杀了他
He told me you killed him.
我就是你的父亲
I am your father.
这不是真的
That's not true.
这不可能！
That's impossible!
问问你的感觉，你会知道这是真的
Search your feelings. You know it to be true.
你可以杀死皇帝，他已经预见到这个了
You can destroy the emperor. He has foreseen this.
这是你的命运
It is your destiny.
加入我吧
Join me…
我们父子一起统治这个银河
and together we can rule the galaxy as father and son.
跟我来
Come with me.
这是唯一的路
It is the only way.
本
Ben.
本，求你了
Ben, please.
听我说
Hear me.
- 我们必须得回去 - 什么？
- We've got to go back. - What?
- 我知道卢克在哪里 - 那那些战斗机怎么对付？
- I know where Luke is. - What about those fighters?
楚伊，照我说的做
Chewie, just do it.
好啦，好啦！
All right, all right!
让我的灭星者级战舰做好准备，等待我抵达
Alert my Stardestroyer to prepare for my arrival.
看，有人在那里
Look, someone's up there.
是卢克，楚伊，放慢
It's Luke. Chewie, slow down.
我们会到他下面的，兰多，打开顶舱门
We'll get under him. Lando, open the top hatch.
好，稳住，楚伊
Okay. Easy, Chewie.
- 兰多？ - 好了，我们走吧
- Lando? - Okay, let's go.
好的，楚伊，我们出发吧
All right, Chewie. Let's go.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
灭星者战舰
Stardestroyer.
好啦，楚伊，准备好光速飞行
All right, Chewie. Ready for light speed.
如果你的人修好了超空间引擎
If your people fixed the hyperdrive.
所有的坐标都输入好了，成败在此一举
All the coordinates are set. It's now or never.
按下它！
Punch it!
他们告诉我他们修好它了
They told me they fixed it.
我信任他们！
I trusted them!
这不是我的错！
It's not my fault!
他们很快就将进入我们的牵引束的作用范围了，大人
They'll be in range of our tractor beam in moments, lord.
你的人破坏了千年鹰号的超空间引擎吗？
Did your men deactivate the hyperdrive on the Millennium Falcon?
- 是的，大人 - 很好
- Yes, my lord. - Good.
准备登机部队，把你的武器调整到击晕状态
Prepare the boarding party and set your weapons for stun.
- 遵命，大人，上尉！ - 遵命，长官
- Yes, my lord. Lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
吵闹的野蛮人，为什么我们还没有进行光速飞行？
Noisy brute. Why don't we just go into light speed?
我们不能进行？
We can't?
你怎么知道超空间引擎被破坏了
How would you know the hyperdrive is deactivated?
城市的中心电脑告诉你的？
The city's central computer told you?
R2-D2，你该知道不能相信一台陌生的计算机
R2-D2, you know better than to trust a strange computer.
喔！注意点，看你在干嘛
Ouch! Pay attention to what you're doing.
父亲
Father.
儿子，跟我来
Son, come with me.
本
Ben.
为什么你没有告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
竟然是维德
It's Vader.
卢克，这是你的命运
Luke, it is your destiny.
你为什么没有告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
让所有单位注意，准备牵引束
Alert all commands. Ready for the tractor beam.
R2，赶快回来！你还没有修完我呢
R2, come back at once! You haven't finished with me yet.
你不知道怎么修复超空间引擎，楚贝卡会修好它的
You don't know how to fix the hyperdrive. Chewbacca can do it.
我在这里分成数块，你却在那里做梦自己会成英雄
I'm standing here in pieces and you're having delusions of grandeur!
你竟然修好了！
You did it!
- 卢克，我们准备起飞了 - 祝你好运，兰多
- Luke, we're ready for take-off. - Good luck, Lando.
等我们找到赫特族的贾巴和赏金猎人，我们会通知你的
When we findJabba the Hutt and that bounty hunter, we'll contact you.
我会在塔图因星上的集合点等着你的
I'll meet you at the rendezvous point on T atooine.
公主殿下，我们会找到汉的，我保证
Princess, we'll find Han. I promise.
楚伊，我等着你的消息
Chewie, I'll be waiting foryour signal.
一切小心
Take care, you two.
愿“原力”与你同在
May the Force be with you.